Finding Aid for Office of the Vice President for Research (University of Michigan), Records, 1950-2001
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- William C. Kelley
  - Central Files, 1986-1991
    - Radiation Safety Committee
      - Rockwell Proposal, 1990 (Box 103)
    - Remote Sensing (GIS/Imaging), 1990 (Box 103)
    - Reproductive Science Program, 1990 (Box 103)
    - Research Excellence Funds, 1989-1990 (Box 103)
    - Research Partnership Program, 1990 (Box 103)
    - Science Development Council, 1990 (Box 103)
    - Science Quest, 1987-1990 (Box 103)
    - Social Research, 1989-1990 (Box 103)
    - Social Work, School of, 1990 (Box 103)
    - Space Physics Research Lab, 1988-1991 (Box 103)
    - State Research Fund, 1990 (Box 103)
    - State Research Relations, 1989-1990 (Box 103)
    - Technology Transfer, 1990 (Box 103)
    - Ultrafast Optical Science, Center for, 1990 (Box 103)
    - Unit for Laboratory Animal Medicine
      - Correspondence, 1990 (Box 103)
      - Public Health Service, 1986-1991 (Box 103)
    - Universities Research Association (Council of Presidents), 1990 (Box 103)
    - UM Transportation Research Institute
      - Correspondence, 1990 (Box 103)
      - Driving Simulator, 1990 (Box 103)
      - Intelligent Vehicle Highway Systems, 1990 (Box 103)
    - Valluga Corporation, 1990 (Box 103)
    - Vice President and Chief Financial Officer, 1990 (Box 103)
    - Vice President for Research-Institution and OVPR Goals, 1986-1989 (Box 103)
    - Vice Provost for Information Technology, 1990 (Box 103)
  - Committees, 1950-1991
    - Animals, Committee on the Use and Care of, Executive Committee
      - 1986-1990, 2 folders (Box 103)
      - 1965-1985 (Box 103)
    - Biophysics Research Division, Executive Committee, 1986-1990 (Box 103)
    - Biosafety Control Committee, 1981-1987 (Box 103)
    - Executive Committee History, 1986 (Box 103)
    - Gerontology, Institute of (IOG), 1982-1990 (Box 103)
    - Great Lakes and Marine Waters Center, Executive Committee, 1977-1987 (Box 103)
    - Human Growth and Development, Center for, 1979-1990 (Box 103)
    - Macromolecular Research Center, Executive Committee, 1972-1989 (Box 103)
    - Middle English Dictionary Advisory Council, 1975-1990 (Box 103)
    - Middle English Dictionary Council, 1978-1991; 2 folders (Box 103)
    - Michigan Memorial Phoenix Project, Executive Committee, 1973-1989 (Box 103)
    - Molecular Genetics, Center for, 1986-1991 (Box 103)
    - Neuroscience Laboratory Building, Executive Committee, 1983-1987 (Box 103)
    - Protein Structure and Design, Program in, Executive Committee, 1985-1990 (Box 103)
    - Radiation Control Service Transfer, 1988 (Box 103)
    - Radiation Policy Committee
      - General, 1983-1988; 4 folders (Box 103)
      - Ad Hoc Committee to Investigate Possible Loss of Coratomic Isotopic-Powered Pacemaker, 1987 (Box 103)
      - Human Use of Radioisotopes, Subcommittee on the, 1972-1988 (Box 103)
      - Meetings
        - December 5, 1988 (Box 104)
        - September 15, 1988 (Box 104)
        - April 5, 1988 (Box 104)
        - January 26, 1988 (Box 104)
        - May 12, 1987 (Box 104)
        - February 6, 1987 (Box 104)
        - November 10, 1986 (Box 104)
        - April 22, 1986 (Box 104)
        - January 24, 1986 (Box 104)
        - 1983-1985 (Box 104)
      - Membership, 1950-1987 (Box 104)
    - Radioactive Drug Research Subcommittee, 1976-1988 (Box 104)
    - Renewal of Byproduct Material License, 1988 (Box 104)
    - Social Research, Institute for, Executive Committee, 1965-1990; 2 folders (Box 104)
    - Ungerleider Memorial Award Committee, 1983-1990 (Box 104)
    - UM Transportation Research Institute, 1972-1990; 2 folders (Box 104)
  - Review Files, 1911-1988
    - Division of Research Development and Administration (DRDA) Review Committee, 1980
      - Correspondence and Materials, 1974-1980; 2 folders (Box 104)
      - Meeting Minutes, 1980 (Box 104)
    - DRDA Review, 1986 (Box 105)
      - Documents, 1911-1986; 4 folders (Box 105)
      - Final Report, 1987 (Box 105)
    - Institute for Social Research
      - Search Committees
        - Report of the ISR Director Search Committee, December 6, 1985 (Box 106)
        - Director Search Materials and Correspondence, 1988-1989 (Box 106)
          [PR RESTRICTED until July 1 2019 ]
      - Visiting Committee
        - General, 1985 (Box 105)
        - Report: Structure, Staff, and Research Activities, 1985 (Box 105)
        - General, 1986; 2 folders (Box 105)
        - Agenda and Materials, 1986 (Box 105)
        - General, 1987; 2 folders (Box 105)
    - Macromolecular Science and Engineering Review
      - General, 1987-1988; 3 folders (Box 105)
      - External Committee Meeting, 1988 (Box 105)
      - Summary of Responses Regarding Macro External and Internal Reports, 1988 (Box 105)
    - Michigan Memorial Phoenix Project, Internal Review Committee Report, 1987 (Box 105)
- OVPR Staff Topical Files, 1984-2001
  Compared to the chronological Central Files, the OVPR Staff Files (7 linear feet) contain more detailed records compiled by OVPR staff members according to their areas of responsibility. Because of the on-going nature of issues in each staff member's portfolio, the records span the tenures of several Vice Presidents for Research, with the series as a whole covering the Vice Presidencies of Alfred Sussman, Linda Wilson, William Kelly, Homer Neal, Frederick Neidhardt, and Fawwaz Ulaby. Moreover, the files represent the work of several OVPR staff members, most notably Administrative Manager Sandy Whitesell and OVPR Research Policy Advisor Judy Nowack. Many of Whitesell's records, which include the files on director searches, indirect costs, space allocation, the OVPR transition, and the ILIR and UMTRI reviews, reflect her role as staff support for OVPR functions carried out by the Linda Wilson, Nowack or Judith Pitney, who was the Director of Planning and Administrative Services. Nowack's own records include the files on the Middle English Dictionary, Research Council, and Unit Grievance Procedures. Also represented are files from Associate VPs Hemalata Dandekar (SRL Review/CSCAR Creation) and Sarah Newman (CHGD and Joint IOG/CHGD/RSP Reviews), and DRDA Director Alan Steiss (RSP Review). These position titles are as of 1989; circa 1996, only Steiss' title remained the same. Judy Nowack had become Assistant VP, Whitesell was Assistant to the VP, and the others had left the Office. Later files thus reflect these changes, with the addition of some records from Jacqueline Hoats (secretary for Judy Nowack), Senior Science Writer Lee Katterman, Associate VP Julie Ellison, Assistant VP Marvin Parnes, and Robert Samors, who worked in the University's Washington, D.C. Office. (Also see Parnes' series for more of his records.)
  This series is notable for its reflection of many changes in the landscape of OVPR responsibilities over the years. Subjects covered include the creation of CSCAR (the Center for Statistical Consulting and Research) and the disbanding of SRL (the Statistical Research Laboratory, more commonly referred to as the 'StatLab') over the period from 1988-1992, the completion of the Middle English Dictionary (in 2001, after over half a century of work on the project), and several transfers of units away from the OVPR to various U-M schools and colleges. These include the transfer of ILIR (the Institute for Labor and Industrial Relations) to the Schools of Business Administration and Social Work in 1991-1993, and the reorganizations of IST (the Institute for Science and Technology), which resulted in the transfer of most of its subunits away from the purview of the OVPR during 1986-1990. The series also includes records on the transition of the OVPR Vice Presidency from Linda Wilson to William Kelly in 1989, which included a proposed change of function of the Vice-President for Research from a Vice-President to a Vice-Provost, with the resulting transfer of the OVPR's reporting lines away from the President to the Provost.
  Another topic of interest reflected in the records are the detailed files on Indirect Cost Distributions. These papers cover the inner workings of indirect costs and how those charges are given back to the units conducting sponsored research in order to pay for various research incentives (such as the cost of GSRAs) and project costs (like telephone charges and research equipment). Finally, Robert Samors' papers highlight his work lobbying Federal and State of Michigan government officeholders on behalf of OVPR in particular and the University in general.
  - Awards, 1997-2000 (Box 128)
    (Corporate and Foundation Alliance, MIT Lemeulson Prize, MI Arts and Humanities Awards)
  - Director and OVPR Position Searches, 1984-1995
    (Most folders in this sub-series include personnel and salary information)
    - Unit for Laboratory Animal Medicine Director Search, 1984-1985 (Box 128)
    - Michigan Memorial Phoenix Project Director Search, 1988 (Box 128)
    - ISR Director Search, 1994
      - Posting, March 1994 (Box 128)
      - Search Committee Meetings, March-June, 1994 (Box 128)
      - Applications and References, April-June 1994 (Box 106)
      - ISR Director Package Offer, June-August 1994 (Box 106)
      - Committee Correspondence, March-December 1994 (Box 106)
    - DRDA Director Search, 1987-1988 (Box 128)
    - Associate VP for Research Searches--Humanities and Social Science, and also Physical Science, 1988 (Box 128)
  - Diversity, 1986-1988
    - Associate VP for Research Search, 1993-1994 (Box 128)
      (Portfolio designed around new hire's specialties and interests)
    - Associate VP for Research--(Humanities and Arts) Search, 1995 (Box 128)
    - E.O.'s (Executive Officers') Mini Retreat on Minority Enrollment Binder, February 1986 (Box 128)
    - Women-Correspondence, February-July 1987 (Box 128)
    - Racism and Affirmative Action, February-December 1987 (Box 128)
    - UM News and Information Service, July 1987-April 1988 (Box 128)
    - DRDA List of Research Projects on Women and Minorities, June 1987 (Box 128)
    - Diversity Statistics, September 1987 (Box 128)
    - Diversity Training Workshops, November 1987-February 1988 (Box 128)
    - Diversity and the Research Community (Symposium), May 6-7, 1988; October 1987-May 1988 (Box 128)
  - Hazardous Waste, 1984-1994
    - Low Level Waste, 1984-1986 (Box 128)
    - (Michigan) DNR (Department of Natural Resources) Mixed Waste Incinerator Facility Dispute, 1991-1994; 2 folders (Box 128)
  - Indirect Cost Distributions, 1986-1995 (Box 129)
    - Formula Allocations, 1986-1994
      - Formula Returns Description, undated (Box 129)
        (Sometime after 1993)
        (Very useful summary and explanation document)
      - Formula Distribution (equipment, rehab, overruns, disallowances), 1986-1989 (Box 129)
      - Formula Allocations for Equipment and Rehabilitation, FY 1990, 1991; September 1989-April 1991 (Box 129)
      - FY 92 E&R and O&D Allocation (Also some FY 1993), October 1991-November 1992 (Box 129)
      - FY 94 Formula Allocations, January-March 1994 (Box 129)
      - Formula Allocations for Equipment and Rehabilitation, FY 1990 and 1991, September 1989-April 1991 (Box 129)
      - FY 92 E&R and O&D Allocation (Also some FY 1993), October 1991-November 1992 (Box 129)
      - FY 94 Formula Allocations, January-March 1994 (Box 129)
    - Research Incentives Programs, 1988-1995
      (In FY 1989 a second Research Incentives Program--R.I.P.2, designed to help sponsored projects defray the cost of hiring GSRAs--was added, so thereafter the original program--designed to provide seed funds for research activities--was designated "R.I.P.1" to distinguish it from the new program.)
      - Research Incentives Planning, 1988 (Box 129)
      - Research Incentives Program FY 1988, October 1987-March 1988 (Box 129)
      - Research Incentives Program FY 1989, October 1988 (Box 129)
      - Research Incentives Program 1 FY 1990, 1989 (Box 129)
      - Research Incentives 1--FY 1991, January 1991 (Box 129)
      - Research Incentives 1--FY 1992, December 1991-January 1992 (Box 129)
      - R.I.P. 1--FY 1993, November 1992 (Box 129)
      - R.I.P. 1--FY 1995, December 1994-January 1995 (Box 129)
      - Research Incentives II, June 1990 (Box 129)
      - R.I.P. 2--FY 92/93, May 1992-January 1993 (Box 129)
    - Project Telephones and Office Equipment, 1986-1992
      - Guidelines for Use of Project Telephone and Equipment Funds, 1986 (Box 129)
      - Project Telephones and Office Equipment Budget Allocation, October 1986-May 1987 (Box 129)
      - Memorandums Project Telephones and Office Equipment, 1986-1987 (Box 129)
      - Announcement in Reporter, April 1987 (Box 129)
      - FY 88 Telephone and Equipment Distribution Letters, 1987 (Box 129)
      - Population Studies Center Project Telephones, 1987; 1990 (Box 129)
        (Includes earlier background material)
      - Project Telephones--FY 1988, May 1987-April 1988 (Box 129)
      - Project Telephones--FY 1989, June-December 1988 (Box 129)
      - Project Telephones--FY 1990, October 1989-April 1990 (Box 129)
        (Folder also includes 3 1/2" computer diskette)
      - Project Telephones--FY 1991, December 1990-January 1991 (Box 129)
      - Project Telephones--FY 1992, November 1991-September 1992 (Box 129)
      - UM Property Insurance for Research Equipment, 1991-1992 (Box 129)
      - Distribution Calculations--Formula and Guides for Project Telephones and Equipment, 1989-1992 (Box 129)
      - FY 1993, Formula Allocations for Phones, Equipment, and O&D, November-December 1992 (Box 129)
  - Intellectual Property Office, 1986-1987 (Box 129)
  - MLK Day, 1990
    - MLK Day 1990 Planning, June 1989-January 1990, 1989-1990 (Box 129)
    - MLK Day 1990 Background Information, December 1988-January 1989, 1988-1990 (Box 129)
  - Middle English Dictionary (MED), 1991-2001
    - Middle English Dictionary, 1991-2000; 2 folders
      - General, 1991-1996 (Box 129)
      - Personnel, 1996-2000 (Box 106)
        [PR RESTRICTED until July 1, 2030 ]
    - MED Annual and Quarterly Reports, 1995-2001 (Box 129)
    - MED Council, 1993-2000 (Box 129)
    - Electronic-MED (eMED), 1994-2000 (Box 129)
    - EMED Initial Concept and Planning, 1992-1994 (Box 129)
    - EMED Meeting Notes, 1994-1996 (Box 129)
    - EMED--Henk Aertsen, 1994-1996 (Box 129)
      (Includes hiring and honoraria information and Social Security Number)
  - OMB Circular A-21 Task Force (Box 130)
    - OMB A-21 Emergency Team, April-June 1994 (Box 130)
    - OMB A-21 Documents, Task Force, and Advisory Group, June 1994-August 1995 (Box 130)
  - OVPR Transition and Linda Wilson's Tenure, 1985-1993
    - OVPR Transition: V.P. Wilson Departs and OVPR Takes on Four New Units 1984 May 1989-Jauary 1990, 1984-1990 (Box 130)
    - Organization Charts, 1986-1990; 1993 (Box 130)
    - Faculty Governance, 1987 (Box 130)
    - LSW (Linda Wilson) Operating Style, 1985-1987 (Box 130)
  - Postdoctoral Certificates, 1985-1989
    - Postdoctoral Certificates--Miscellaneous, 1985-1988 (Box 130)
    - Postdoctoral Certificates, 1986-1989; 9 folders (Box 130)
  - Research Council (RC), 1995-1999
    - Research Council, 1995-1999 (Box 130)
    - Membership, 1995-1997 (Box 130)
    - Meetings, 1995-1997 (Box 130)
    - Paper Communications to RC, 1995-1996 (Box 130)
  - Reviews, 1980-1994 (Box 130)
    (includes earlier background material)
    - Statistical Research Laboratory (SRL) / Center for Statistical Consulting and Research (CSCAR) Transition, 1982-1992
      (Also includes earlier background material)
      - SRL History and OVPR Files, 1974; 1982-1990
        - 1974 (Box 131)
          (Transfer from Rackham to OVPR)
        - 1982 (Box 131)
          (Letters of support for SRL and invitations to review committee)
        - 1983-1984 (Box 131)
          (Review and reorganization into separate Statistical Consulting and Statistical Computing Units)
    - Statistical Research Laboratory (SRL) / Center for Statistical Consulting and Research (CSCAR) (cont.)
      - SRL History and OVPR Files 1974, 1982-1990 (cont.), 1974-1990
        - 1982 (Box 131)
        - 1983-1984 (Box 131)
        - 1985-1989 (Box 131)
          (Including 1987 Review, 1987/1988 user surveys, and Technology Transfer Agreement with Scientia)
        - 1990 (Box 131)
      - Statistical Computing Unit (SCU) Review Committee, 1989-1990
        - Composition, September-November 1989 (Box 131)
        - Charge, September-December 1989 (Box 131)
        - Notes re Review Process, November 1989-February 1990 (Box 131)
        - Minutes, November 1989-March 1990 (Box 131)
        - Correspondence with Committee, October 1989-July 1990 (Box 131)
          (Includes background material from 1988)
        - Correspondence with William Kelly / (Virginia) Nordby / (Daniel) Sharphorn, August 1989-April 1990 (Box 131)
        - Correspondence with Fox, July 1989-June 1990 (Box 131)
        - Correspondence with Outsiders, June 1989-May 1990 (Box 131)
        - Royalties on MIDAS and TEXTEDIT, 1990
          (Includes royalty distribution information)
          (Background material from 1976-1985)
        - Final Report and Director's Comments on the Review, April-May 1990 (Box 131)
        - Final Report Volume 2 (Source Documents) (Box 131)
        - SCU Implementation, April-July 1990 (Box 131)
        - Significant Documents (SRL/SCU History), 1984-1989 (Box 131)
      - Special Task Force on Statistical Support, 1988-1991
        - Stat Task Force, February 1988-January 1989 (Box 131)
        - Final Report, February 1989 (Box 131)
        - Discussion of Report, March-June, 1989 (Box 131)
        - Follow-up, June 1989-March 1990 (Box 131)
        - Requests for CSCAR Reports, 1989-1991 (Box 131)
      - Statistical Computing Implementation Committee (SCIC), March-July 1990
        - SCIC, March-July 1990 (Box 131)
        - Final Report, June 1990 (Box 131)
      - CSCAR Transition and Directory Search Committees, 1990-1992
        - CSCAR Transition Committee, June 1990-June 1991 (Box 131)
        - Transition Committee Meetings and Survey, October 1990; January 1991 (Box 131)
          (Meetings and Survey distribution in October, results analysis in January)
        - Commentary from (Users on) Computer Conference System, June 1990-April 1991 (Box 132)
        - CSCAR Search Committee, June-October 1990 (Box 132)
        - CSCAR Advertisements, August-November 1990 (Box 132)
        - Nominations, July 1990-March 1991 (Box 132)
        - TEXTEDIT Phase-out, September 1990-June 1992 (Box 132)
    - IST, 1984-1990
      - IST Review, 1984-1986
        - Budget Priorities Committee Discussions (on whether a review should occur), 1984 (Box 132)
          (Includes background material from 1978)
        - IST Review, January 1985-March, 1986 (Box 132)
          (In January-March, 1986 William Kelly is chosen as the new IST Director, and thus must leave the Review Committee, just as the Committee's report is in its final stages of deliberation)
        - IST Director Search, September 1985-March 1986 (Box 132)
        - Comments on the IST Review, April-September, 1986 (Box 132)
      - IST Realignment, 1986-1990
        - LSW's (Linda Wilson's) Notes on Development of IST Realignment Problem, April 1986-October 1987 (Box 132)
        - IST Change, October-November 1986 (Box 132)
        - IST Proposal, July 1987 (Box 132)
        - IST Meeting (Linda Wilson and) Shapiro, Duderstadt, and Kennedy, July 1987 (Box 132)
        - IST Proposal Public Comments, June-October, 1987 (Box 132)
        - LSW's (Linda Wilson's) IST Realignment File, 1988 (Box 132)
        - IST/OIA (Institute of Science and Technology / Office of Interdisciplinary Activities), 1989-1990 (Box 132)
        - Space Administration, 1987-1990 (Box 132)
      - IST--OVPR Chronological Files, 1985-1990; 5 folders (Box 132)
    - Institute of Gerontology/Center for Human Growth and Development/Reproductive Studies Program Joint Review, 1991-1992
      - Joint Internal Review Binder, 1991-1992 (Box 133)
      - Proposed Joint External Review, 1991-1992 (Box 133)
    - Institute for Labor and Industrial Relations Review Committee, 1991-1994
      (Also earlier background material)
      - Charge, 1991-1992 (Box 133)
      - Agendas and Meeting Minutes, 1992 (Box 133)
      - Committee Deliberations, 1992 (Box 133)
      - Michigan AFL-CIO Letters, 1992-1993 (Box 133)
      - Data, 1992 (Box 133)
        (Also includes background material from 1991 and earlier)
      - ILIR Peer Institutions Survey, 1992-1993 (Box 133)
      - Meares Vita--Social Work, 1993 (Box 133)
      - ILIR Executive Committee, 1991-1992 (Box 133)
      - ILIR Staff Bio Sketches, undated (Box 133)
      - Final Report, 1992-1993 (Box 133)
      - Transfer to Social Work/Business, 1993-1994 (Box 133)
      - ILIR Tenure, 1992-1993 (Box 133)
      - Malcolm Cohen and Andrea Foote Transitions, 1993 (Box 106)
        [CR RESTRICTED until July 1, 2093 ]
    - Center for Human Growth and Development, 1992-1993
      (Also includes background material from the 1980s)
      - External Review Committee, 1992; 1987
        - Membership, February-April 1992 (Box 133)
        - Materials Distributed to Committee, March-May 1992 (Box 133)
        - Strategic CHGD Retreat Notes, 1987 (Box 133)
        - Faculty Input, April-June 1992 (Box 133)
        - Report Revisions, May-September 1992 (Box 133)
        - Miscellaneous, March-October 1992 (Box 133)
        - Follow-through on Report, June-November 1992 (Box 133)
      - Betsy Lozoff, August-October 1992 (Box 133)
      - Intercollegiate Review Committee, 1992-1993
        - Initial Planning and Membership, October-November 1992 (Box 133)
        - Meeting Deliberations and Committee Report, November 1992-June 1993 (Box 133)
    - University of Michigan Transportation Research Institute, 1992-1993
      - Review Planning, July 1992-July 1993 (Box 133)
      - UMTRI Executive Committee, March 1993 (Box 133)
      - UMTRI 1985 Review Report, May 1985 (Box 133)
      - University and Local Reviewers, November 1992-April 1993 (Box 133)
      - External Reviews, February-August 1993 (Box 133)
    - Reproductive Studies Program Review Committee, 1990-1994
      - Membership, 1993 (Box 133)
      - Agenda and Minutes, September-November 1993 (Box 133)
      - External Correspondence, 1990; 1992-1993 (Box 133)
      - Deliberations and Internal Correspondence, September-November 1993 (Box 133)
      - Background Material, 1984-1993 (Box 133)
      - Report, 1993-1994 (Box 133)
  - Samors, Robert, 1993-1999
    - Anthrax Project, 1998 (Box 133)
    - Cloning and Stem Cell Research, 1997-1998 (Box 133)
    - Copyright Legislation, 1998 (Box 133)
    - Earmarking, 1993-1994 (Box 134)
    - Federal Policy Working Groups, 1998-1999 (Box 134)
    - Intelligent Transportation Systems Funding, 1998 (Box 134)
    - Life Sciences Commission, 1998-1999 (Box 134)
    - Michigan Fish and Wildlife Cooperative Unit, 1998-1999 (Box 134)
    - National Institute of Nursing Research, 1997-1999 (Box 134)
    - National Science Foundation (NSF) FY 2000, Budget, 1999 (Box 134)
    - NSF Information Technology for the 21st Century (IT2), 1999 (Box 134)
    - OMB Circular A-110 Release of Data, 1998-1999 (Box 134)
    - Public Health Research and NIH Funding, 1997-1999 (Box 134)
  - Space Allocations, 1986-1993
    - General Issues, 1986-1993
      - Space Rental Summaries, 1989-1990 (Box 134)
      - OVPR Space Inventory, 1989-1992 (Box 134)
      - OVPR Space Analysis and Priorities, 1986-1993 (Box 134)
      - Disruption of Research due to Construction, 1986-1987; 1995 (Box 134)
    - Specific Buildings and Programs, 1987-1993
      - AIDS Space/Alcohol Research Center, 1987-1988 (Box 134)
      - Cochlear Ear Space, 1987-1988 (Box 134)